Josh Pattison

Full-Stack Software Engineer

f joshpattison.com



in

linkedin.com/in/josh-pattison

Personal Profile

Before moving into tech, I achieved a BSc in Psychology. I have always wanted to help people and the best way I can help thousands of people is with code.

Therefore, my focus is on creating helpful software that is comprised of clean and well tested code. I am a highly motivated and curious person. I am also passionate about creating beautiful experiences with my code.

I find great pleasure in solving problems and I am experienced in doing this individually, or as part of a team.

Experience

Full Stack Development, The School of Code – Remote. April 2022 – Present.

- Chosen from thousands of applications.
- Focused on learning and using full stack technologies to solve real world problems in programming teams.
- Worked in 13 diverse teams over 16 weeks. Mainly pair programming but I also worked in a 4-person team for a weeklong project and a 5-person team for a four-week project.

Four-week project.

- Used agile methodologies in a team of five to create a full-stack travel application whereby users could find unbiased information on countries in the world to better inform their destination decisions. This was built using React, CSS, AuthO, AWS Gateway, AWS Lambda and DynamoDB.
- I had a role in setting up and deploying the backend.
- Spent a lot of time building the front-end with React and styling it with CSS.
- I was responsible for inputting github actions in our project.
- I was also responsible for editing our final presentation video.
- We used agile methodologies such as daily stand-ups, retrospectives, SCRUM (experienced SCRUM leadership) and pair programming.
- Used a variety of project management and design tools such as Miro, Figma, Trello and Slack.

References available on request.

Other experience

Delivery Driver, Dominos – Bedworth. May 2018 – Present.

- A job role that encourages both teamwork and independence.
- When on delivery I work independently but when working in store I work as part of a team improving my teamwork skills.

Volunteering

Call Companion, Re-engage – Remote. December 2021 – Present.

- I make regular phone calls to a lonely and isolated older person to provide a line of friendship.
- These friendly chats provide the older person with a link to the outside world from which they have become isolated.

Skills

Languages – HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, SQL.

Libraries & Frameworks — Node.js, React, Express.js, TailwindCSS, Next.js.

Hosting – Heroku, Netlify, AWS, Vercel.

Testing – Jest, Cypress, Postman.

Databases – PostgreSQL, AWS.

Personal –

Empathetic, Flexible, Communicative.

Interests

- I really enjoy sports specifically football and Formula 1. I love the combination of both individual and team dynamics that these sports showcase.
- Next would-be gaming, this links mainly to enjoying time spent with family and friends.
- I enjoy nature. Nice walks and trying my best to grow plants!
- I also enjoy anime/manga. My current favourite is Demon Slayer.

Education

BSc Psychology, Coventry University. Sept 2018 – May 2022.

- Upper Second Class, 2:1.

Carbon Literacy, Coventry University. July 2021.

- Certificate to show I have met all requirements of the Carbon Literacy Standard.

Microsoft Office Specialist, Coventry University. Jan 2019.



- Learnt how to use Excel to a professional level.

A-Levels, King Edward VI College. Sept 2016 – July 2018.

- History, Geography and Law.

GCSEs, Ash Green Academy. Sept 2011 – July 2016.

- 11 GCSEs A-C, including English and Mathematics.
- Head boy of the Academy.